### Donovan Lo

Singapore



## **PROFILE**

An intelligent solution-oriented thinker who is always challenging myself to find better ways to getting things done. I believe that there is great potential in each individual and enjoy helping others to move forward, grow, and reach their fullest potential.

Possesses practical knowledge in non-profits and social sector with cross sector knowledge and experience ranging from day-to-day operations, HR, accounting, social media, fund raising, IT, programme development, public health, charity and IPC governance. Independent, self-initiated person who can undertake complex assignments, meet deadlines and delivers.

Open to ideas and able to find and understand the logical connections between them. I have an efficient perception of reality and together with strong analytical skills, I can solve problem systematically, identify needs, and develop innovative strategy for a long term sustainable programme supported with evidence-based proposal.

I gained experience in the variety of projects I involved. I have start up an organisation from scratch, lead teams and grown their capabilities. I set up strategic directions, business models, operation processes and oversee different programmes targeting different groups. I have collaborated with ministries, statutory board, corporate and non-profit group to ensure the programme's positive impact.

Core competencies include: Project Management, Financial Statements, Programme Development Community Partnership, Strategic Planning, Budgeting, Public Health (HIV-related), Database Development, Information Technology.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

Centre Director

Aug 2015 – May 2017

### Stroke Support Station Ltd

- > Start up the organisation which is serving 120 members, 75 caregivers with 150 volunteers.
- > Led a team of 4 managers and an executive, grown from 2 part-time administrative staff, to deliver different programme from wellness programme to improve the abilities of stroke survivors to doing outreach to create awareness.

#### Donovan Lo

Singapore



- > Obtained IPC status in the first year of operation and renewed the IPC status for another two years after.
- > Assess mission of the organisation, crystallised ideas and devise unique scalable and sustainable franchised-readied business model.
- > Developed operating procedures, accounting process and set up chart of account complying to FRS and compatible with CAS.
- > Developed a unique modular programme structure to provide customised improvement intervention with activities, developed by professional medical doctors and therapist, to individual stroke survivor in a group setting.
- > Assist in organising a fund raising within a short time frame of two and a half months, attracted more than one thousand guests and raised 1.6 million.
- > Collaborate with HPB to organise a Stroke Awareness Public Forum attracting 300 participants.
- > Create online presence with website and Facebook with 6,000 followers.
- > Develop staff capabilities, equipping them with skills like project management, programme development, mind mapping skills etc.
- > Setup SharePoint and populate it with relevant information and knowledge and introduce collaborative software to facilitate communications in the organisation.

## General Manager

Jan 2014 – Apr 2015

# Cheng Hong Welfare Service Society

- > Start out as only full time non-medical staff handling almost a full spectrum of organisation functions
- > Recruit and train a team of key staffs
- > Strategize and proposal action plans for Pro Bono Afterlife Memorial Service and secure long-term funds to fund for it.
- > Resolve issues and ensure adherence to charity governance and guidelines. Implement policies and procedures.
- > Successful application of \$100,000 grant for healthcare assistance programme
- > Implemented Charity Accounting Standards.

### Donovan Lo

Singapore



Executive Director
Senior Programme Manager
Programme Manager

Apr 2011 – Dec 2013 Jan 2010 – Apr 2011 Oct 2008 – Dec 2010

# Action for AIDS (AfA) Singapore

- > Managed the operation with an annual budget of \$1.4 million with total asset of \$3.2 million and caring for more than 200 beneficiaries annually.
- > Lead a team of managers, executives and coordinators, which grew from 4 to 12, to deliver impactful HIV related programmes, develop public health IEC materials, each handling different programmes.
- > Ensuring full compliance of the Code of Governance and statutory requirements and renew IPC Status.
- > Rapport building with MOH, HPB, CPF, Sector Administrator and Auditors to effectively tackle issues like Code of Governance, Norm Costs, referrals, means testing, subventions, remuneration & funding
- > Take over account and handled audits for two consecutive years.
- > Handled the public relations for coming out of the 2nd PLHIV in Singapore
- > Achieved excellent in performance appraisal continuously for five years.
- > Initiate and execute several education and awareness projects (e.g. Anniversary Short Film by Royston Tan, BePositive Campaigns)
- > Pioneer several outreach programmes (e.g. transgender outreach programme, male sex walker outreach programme)

#### **EDUCATION**

BSc (Hons) in Computing

*Mar 2003 to Mar 2004* 

Coventry University

Upper Second Honours Majoring in Computing

Advance Diploma in Computer Studies

Aug 2000 to Dec 2002

validated by University of Cambridge

NCC Diploma in Computer Studies

Mar 1992 to Sep 1993

validated by National Centre for Information Technology (UK)

GCE 'O' Level

1987 to 1990

Temasek Secondary School

Singapore



#### OTHER CERTIFICATION

- > Advanced Certificate in Training and Assessment (ACTA)
- > Microsoft Certified Professional Course (MCSE)
- > Microsoft Certified Solution Developer Course
- > Oracle Database Designing Courses
- > Lucent Technologies PABX Administration and Programming Course)
- Certificate of Achievement for NCSS SSTI Courses (e.g. Facilitating Effective Meeting and Discussion, Strategic Thinking for NPO Board and Management, Understanding the Regulations and Code of Governance for Charities and IPCs)

### IT SKILLS

- > MS Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access, Outlook),
- > Desktop Publishing (e.g. Adobe Photoshop)
- > Web Application Development (e.g. ColdFusion)
- > Customer Relationship Management (Onyx Customer Center)
- > Database Development (SQL)
- > Helpdesk and Ticketing System
- > Accounting Software (e.g. MYOB)
- > Mind mapping software
- > Team Collaboration SaaS
- > Windows Servers
- > Social Media

#### COMMITTEE

- > Executive Member of Pasir Ris Zone 4 Residents' Committee from 1998-2001
- > Ministry of Health Working Committee on MSM and HIV/AIDS

#### NATIONAL SERVICE

- > NSF: Oct 93 to Oct 95
- > Certificate of Service: Conduct Very Good , Performance Very Good
- > Outstanding serviceman of the month for month of September 95